Good morning, Karen.
>> I haven't seen you in a while.
>> How are you?
>> Good. How are you?
>> Great.
>> Hi, buddy.
>> Are you ready?
>> Are you ready? [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> Okay. What do you got here?
>> Uh we haven't spoken to you uh since
agency.
>> That's why I'm smiling.
>> Uh how do you feel about uh your free
agency class? And also Elliot had shared
with us a while back that he thought
giving what accomplished the saying he
would have to draft.
>> Well, I don't think you should ever
draft for need. Um,
you know, that's that's not a position
that you ever want to be in. We again I
like uh I love all our players. You
know, certainly the the the free agents
that we were able to acquire
was a collaborative e effort between the
coaches and the personnel and you know
myself and being able to to add guys
that we believe in and that can help us.
Um and then we'll continue to add guys
and that's kind of how this thing goes.
But I do think that um every year is
different. there's change in coaching
staff and the personnel and the players
and you know like the guys that we were
able to add and we'll continue to try to
strengthen the roster.
>> You uh happy with the
>> happy you a happy guy.
>> Do you like where your wide receiver
room is right now with Doss and Rudy and
Kyle Williams?
there there's guys that we certainly we
targeted Romeo, you know, with the
consistency that that he's had and shown
and
his first four years in the NFL and I
think he's gotten better. I think he's
improved each and every year. Certainly,
you mentioned Kahan. I think Pop is a
player that's going to really continue
to grow and develop and we have to find
ways to get him the ball.
Kyle really excited. Talked about him
just improving his play strength and you
know that's something that he's tried to
focus on here in the offseason.
We know what his speed is and his
release skills and you know the ability
to to you know we saw him you go and
track the ball down the field. So you
know there there's a lot of guys that
we're excited about.
>> You sort of scripted out production
thing. Steph had 85 catches and a
thousand odd yards. How does that
continue up or do you need more? Um,
you know, I don't know how that gets
divy. I mean, it's about it's literally
about targets and you know, so when you
get targeted and again the efficiency, I
really we we all appreciate what Steph
did and and really loved being able to
coach him,
but you know what has to happen is the
efficiency in which he was able to catch
the ball uh was was impressive. So
whether that's Drake's accuracy,
uh, ball location, or Steph's ability
to, uh, to to catch it, that's something
that we'll have to recreate. And I'm not
worried about the the catches and the
overall production. I think we can re
recreate that. We just have to be very
mindful that uh, the efficiency in which
we um, throw and catch it is important.
>> Mike,
Mike, what kind of uh, player person.
Are the Bears getting at Gary Bradford?
>> Well, they're getting uh somebody that
loves football, loves his teammates.
[snorts]
Um, you know, he brought a certainly a
leadership to us that that we needed
last year. Um, there was a consistency,
durability,
>> that that's what they're getting. you
know, they're getting they're getting a
pro who's going to be prepared. He's
going to make the calls. He's going to
communicate. Uh but but Garrett also
loves the process of of football, you
know, the offseason,
the weekly preparation with his
teammates and his coaches.
>> Mike, today the owners are going to be
voting on a proposal to allow more over
to um the replay center to overturn
calls on the field in case of the CBA
expires to the officials. Do you think
that is a better alternative? I think
that's foolproof enough if that if it
comes to that to avoid a 2012.
>> I think they should let the coaches call
their own fouls, you know. I mean,
that's, you know, that's what they
should do.
>> Mike, um, what Mike, what do you got,
buddy? You guys, I want to appreciate
the local media and I know that we have
our little spats, but I appreciate
everything that you guys do to cover us.
um when I first got here, I wanted to,
you know, bring our fans back and you
guys are the extension to that and and
make sure that our fans are um
knowledgeable and they're prepared to to
watch us. So, I want to thank all you
guys that do that,
>> Sam. And I think we try to represent
like the fans like what they want asked
and and uh I know it's hard. It's hard
on on So, here's one on on X.
>> Trivia quoted some Bible verses
supporting um a Chicago Bulls player who
got released for okay
>> some um
>> some comments that he made. And I just
how do you measure the line between um
conduct detrimental to the team, which
is why the Bulls released the player in
their view, and allowing a 23-year-old
to you know express his personal
burdens.
>> I think there is a fin tell you I love
Tia. I love the person um there. He
cares deeply about our team. He cares
deeply about his faith. He cares deeply
about his family, uh his wife, um the
people in our building. And so I want
them to be able to express what they
believe in their heart and in their
mind, but but also want to make sure
that they're educated. And we want to be
inclusive. We want to everything we want
to do uh wants to provide an environment
for people to one feel comfortable but
also to share their personal beliefs uh
and then also we represent the team and
we represent the organization.
>> We like talk to him about or like talk
to the team about generally. I I usually
try to I think that's something that we
try to do Nicole constantly like there's
[clears throat] you know it's like
somebody asked me last year how you
going to keep them off their phones like
let let yeah keep you guys off your
phones. There's 19 phones laying on the
table. We just want to educate them to
um
never going to tell them how to feel.
certainly want to be make sure that they
understand that their actions represent
something more than just themselves. And
so I do think there's a fine line. We're
always talking about those kinds of
things. We're trying to educate them. No
different than myself or or you guys or
or my kids.
>> Signing Reggie Hill, Elijah Vera Tucker.
Seems like there's a focus on kind of
getting bigger, running the ball more
consistently. How much is that, I guess,
a focus of the offseason to kind of get
more?
>> Well, I mean, I felt like we
>> I just want to be more consistent. We,
the Patriots, want to be more consistent
running the football. This isn't like
we're going to run it every single play.
It It's just that I felt like there were
too many times where we wanted to run it
and it was just inefficient. Now, we we
popped some, which were great. We had
some explosives and so then when you go
back there and you average it all out,
it's like, okay. But I would I want to
be able to do it more consistently to
allow for then,
>> you know, some of the the run actions in
the passing game to really come alive
and just to to start to uh help us. It
it's a tough league if you have to sit
there and drop back and throw the
football um as much as we did in the
last game of the season.
>> But know that Barrett Tucker had some
has had some injury issues. Did having
Ben Brown on the roster make you feel
more comfortable about that? Ben's I I
don't know if those two things
necessarily,
>> you know, go hand in hand.
I love Ben Brown. I love the teammate
that he is. I love his ability to be
versatile and play center and play guard
and uh be prepared and every week
prepare as a starter. I love that about
Ben. He's a great teammate,
you know. Then Elijah was just a player
that we felt like had a um skill set and
talent um you know understand the
injuries and you know so we just felt
like we wanted to add his talent to the
roster.
>> What do you call Campbell benefit from
playing next?
>> I mean I think just you know guy that's
been out there a guy that's been you
know a first round pick. Um, you know, I
think he's by all accounts, Elijah's a
good teammate. Never coached him, but
um, you know, excited to add him,
you know, to to the O line. Um, Will's a
young player. We'll continue to develop,
continue to improve, and, you know,
we're excited to keep working with him.
>> A move for, as I said, someone like AJ
Brown would still be on the table at
this point.
We we've talked about this since last
January. We're going to try to do
everything we can to strengthen our
roster um through the draft, through
free agency,
multiple ways of player acquisition. So,
anything that we can continue to do to
strengthen the roster, we're going to
try to do. [clears throat and cough]
>> Still have cap space available for any
big moves if you want to make them.
>> I do a lot of things. Focus on cap space
is not one of them. I I don't you know I
mean we've been Robert and Jonathan have
given us all the resources that we've
needed since I've been here uh to sign
players the amazing facility that we
just moved into last Monday. Um so I'll
let Elliot and Ryan and Richard and Matt
Grow focus on the cap space
>> if you say so.
>> How do you feel? So, you want to acquire
somebody in a trade. What's your thought
about surrendering draft picks,
particularly in next year's draft?
>> Um,
I mean, compensation is compensation.
you have you know and you have to agree
to something and whether it's
capital in this year's draft or you know
Cleveland's proposing or Cleveland had
proposed something extend you know be
able to trade five years out that's not
going to be uh available to us but
you know I just uh however you can come
to an agreement with another team
you know I've never really
looked at it as this year, next year,
how good the draft is in three years,
and just try to come to an agreement. If
you if you make a trade, you just want
to try to come to agreement that both
teams feel like they're getting
something that they um that everybody's
happy. [clears throat]
>> Played and involved with the NFL PA, how
would you feel about the possibility of
adding an 18th game,
>> Mark? Yeah, I mean I'll support whatever
uh both sides,
you know, come to an agreement on. Um
I I'll coach as many games as they want
me to coach. I love, as you can see,
coaching our football team. Last year,
again, it was a end to a great year, and
I'll coach as many games as they asked
me to coach. with your attack depth of
vidarian San Fran and they are still a
free agent adding depth to that position
helping for priority team
>> um
>> we have to the league has to develop
offensive linemen we have to we you know
it's a critical important position for
the game to protect our quarterbacks
that are so valuable to this league um
So whether we draft them, whether we
sign them, whatever we do, we have to be
able to continue to develop um offensive
linemen uh to to be able to protect our
quarterback. It's such a critical
position. So however we can continue to
do that, I want to do that.
>> Uh yeah, maybe they're going to wrap up.
I we've got, you know, we got to get
back for draft meetings.
Um
but and then we got some guys coming in
on 30 visits. Um but if I can get back
out there, I I'll get back out there.
>> Mike, what did you guys get out of your
injury? I know he's a player you just
set to let go, but what were the
positives that he brought to your team?
>> Uh
you know, just touching on his
professionalism. Every day he came to
work, he was prepared,
really led the offensive line.
great energy, connection with the
quarterback, his durability,
consistency.
>> Mike, can you give us any kind of update
on how Harold is doing and how do you
feel about your edge rusher position
going forward?
>> Um,
Harold continues to rehab. Um,
you know, I just, uh, disappointed
obviously for him and for us because
I've known Harold for for quite a while.
you know, a player I became really close
with. We drafted him in Tennessee,
did a great job for us there. And it's
just unfortunate, I think, that anybody
that watched the tape could see, you
know, Harold before hurting his knee and
then after. And so, another player that
cares deeply about the team and his
performance and the impact that he
makes. And so I was uh disappointed for
him, but he like everything else works
his tail off right now to to get back.
And so I don't really know where it's at
right now because it's going through the
rehab process. With that being said, you
know, we'll continue to strengthen each
and every position,
whether that's the interior, the
defensive line, that's the edge, inside
linebacker, you know. So again, like the
guys that we have, that that doesn't
mean that we won't continue to try to
add to that position.
>> You bring in Draymond. Is he like an
edge only? Can you shift him inside a
little bit?
>> There's versatility. Obviously, you
know, there's versatility that
>> you know, it's so critical when you only
have, you know, 48 players on the active
roster on Sundays. Eight of them are O
linemen. They're not doing anything but
blocking.
Two of them are quarterbacks. Last year
there was three of them. You got a
kicker, a punter, snap. You start to get
the list gets limited there. So, when
you have guys that can play more than
one position, um
>> linebacker or safety and maybe a, you
know, linebacker on third down or a
subbacker or you have an outside
linebacker that can go inside on third
down or passing downs. We will we we
would love to have as many players that
are versatile as possible.
>> Mike, you the decision to have the joint
practice with the Eagles. Why did you
want to work with the Eagles and Nick
Serani? What do you hope to get out of
this practice?
>> I I didn't and I didn't think we were
going to, but then Nick said something
yesterday, so I guess we're kind of
forced into doing it.
>> What do you
>> They're a talented football team. Um I
have a lot of respect for Nick. have a
lot of respect for Howy, Mr. Lurri. Um,
just their consistency over the last
four or five years, you know, of very
good football. Uh, felt like that would
be a, you know, good opportunity for us
to to go against a really good football
team.
>> Hey, Mike, obviously you're known for
and giving your personality on the
defensive side of the ball. I'm curious
when you scan over the offensive side,
how much do you look for uh the
composition of just what the personality
is even on that side of the ball and
whether that edge factor from a
personality stand what you think is
somewhat dissipated with the cars define
and whether you need to infuse that
aspect of it still on the offensive
side.
>> Well, certainly I think that identity is
is critical no matter [clears throat]
what position that you play. Um
I love Steph's energy. uh loved uh who
he is as a person. Certainly, we talked
about the production. So, I don't
whether you play offense or defense,
we're we're going to need guys that uh
have great identity and uh bring energy
in their own way to the football team.
>> Obviously, I know that AJ's on a
different
>> followup.
>> And what' you say?
>> Followup.
>> That's a [laughter]
um I obviously I know that AJ's on a
different team or what have you. One of
the things that um you do obviously have
a past relationship with him. One of the
things that has been kind of going back
and forth with him is uh you know what
is his um not only just rapport with his
teammates but somehow that how that his
desire to be great gets misunderstood.
So just even when you're talking about
him or just a player um players overall
do you feel like you know you can
distinguish between a player you know
being wanting to think about their
legacy and being great and and and how
that doesn't get misinterpreted so
there's a problem on the team.
>> Sure. I will say this, I love the
relationship that I have with my players
on our team and the ones on other teams
that I've either coached or come in
contact with. That's the the beauty of
this league. And having played it and
being able to coach it, the the men and
the the people involved on the field uh
is something that's special that I hold
uh very near and dear. Have
communications with a lot of those
players. Now, we all understand in
professional sports, players that are
talented and get to this level have some
sort of ego to them and and there's a
balance, right? What's, you know, they
have to have that edge. Uh, and so I
think as a coaching staff and whatever
that is, you have to balance that edge
to make sure that that's helping the
team. And we all have, everybody wants
to
excel. What receiver doesn't want to
catch the ball? What pass rusher doesn't
want to sack the quarterback? What DB
doesn't want to intercept the ball? Like
that's just what's the running backs
want to score touchdowns. That's how
this thing goes. So there's a balance
between their own personal success and
their mindset and then how they can help
the team.
>> Mike said yesterday we felt you guys
overachieved last year. Um do you agree
with that? And
>> we I talked to Robert about that. I him
and I had a really good conversation.
He said it's going to be a tougher
schedule and a tougher tougher road and
playoffs remain the goal. What do you
look at this season? Obviously,
>> championships will remain the goal. They
will never change.
Uh appreciate, you know, Robert's
support, but we want to
win the division. We want to host
playoff games, and we want to compete
for championships. And so, we got a
taste of that. We saw what that looked
like. We saw the environment that it
created to be able to play those playoff
games at home. Uh, which was
unbelievable and and so much fun. Just
watch the reactions. I watched the
videos of the f because that's the part
that I really didn't get to appreciate
coaching the game is seeing the fan
videos, you know, the the videos from
the fans in that perspective. Um, so,
you know, we'll play whoever we have to
play. We understand what this looks
like. We're going to play the division
winner schedule and uh
>> that's how it goes.
>> I mean remember
>> everything about this league is hard.
>> Difficult season for you guys. You got
everybody's best shot having
accomplished what you did the year
before.
>> Again, we only have 17 games. I hope
each and every week they're getting our
best shot and we're getting their best
shot. that that we're not going to have
a job if that's not if we don't do that.
>> How do you feel about appearing?
>> Can't wait.
>> Mike, connectivity was such a big theme
among the players last year. They felt
like some said it was the closest team
it had ever been on.
>> How much thought at this point have you
put into how do you create that again?
>> A lot. You know, I just
we spend a lot of time together, you
know, and uh and we all come from
different backgrounds. We
some of players are going to be coming
back. Some of them are new. We're going
to add rookies and other players to the
team. So, continue to try to find ways
to to do that without being, you know,
never want to make it a gimmick. that's
important to me that it's not gimmicky
that what we do is authentic and real
and genuine.
>> To that point,
>> there were different elements of um that
you would things that you would put up
on the walls um motto, slogans, etc.
>> Not that much.
>> There was not many signs. You guys saw
them all.
>> Yeah. Is that
>> Do you keep that stuff around? Do you
build a new culture in different ways?
Uh
>> I don't think build a new culture. I
think you just try to enhance on the
culture and you believe in the identity,
you know, honesty, connection, respect,
accountability, you know, things that we
want to, you know, winning,
competitiveness,
those aren't up on a wall anywhere, you
know, I mean, those are just what we
want to be as people and and then try to
make connections uh on buy the stuff
that we feel like is important. What's
the biggest [clears throat]
you want to see from Drake in his third
year, second year?
>> I I think his ability to control the
game at the line of scrimmage, whether
that's operationally getting us into a
better play, you know, continue to take
ownership of the offense. I mean, he's
an extension of Josh and Josh sends the
play in. We want Drake to to own it, to
own the play. and you know bring it to
life with the with cadence communication
you know all the motion and all the
things you know orchestrate
uh continue to do that there's nothing
physically
um is very talented you know so continue
to to push him to lead and and to try to
orchestrate
um and conduct the offense
>> mentioning the new facility how can that
setup help what you guys do
>> well it's just From an efficiency
standpoint, I think it's an from an
energy. I think when our players come in
on April 20th, I think there's going to
be an energy. They're going to enjoy uh
coming to work just from the how nice it
is, the functionality, the space, all
those types of things. So, um, be able
to be a great place for learning, great
place to develop our players and,
you know,
just the wait room to the training room
to the to the locker room, cafeteria,
you know, just the meeting space that we
have is is going to be really nice.
>> Mike, I know better than to ask you
about the potential for replacement
officials. However, the New York command
center, the officiating center, in your
time, paying very close attention to how
they adjudicate calls, how do you view?
[laughter]
>> Google that.
>> How do you feel the the officiating
center does? And have you wanted to see?
>> I they do as good a job as they possibly
can in the time that they have allotted
to them. Um there are some calls that
are very difficult. Um you know I think
the big one is the the quarterback. Uh
whether it's the tuck or the fumble or
the pass. It's
stretch and I just bet whatever the call
on the field is, we're going to let that
one stand because that's probably not
getting overturned. So, um I I I think
that they um try to use a standard of
clear and obvious and uh the biggest
thing is that we understand what they
believe to be clear and obvious.
>> Mike, your experience last year,
>> hey buddy.
>> Bringing in guys that you knew and and
figuring out guys that you didn't know.
How do you kind of navigate between
that? How is there a risk to bringing in
a guy that you don't know? I think that
there's um you just have to be very
careful. I mean, in free agency, I think
that you're referring to,
it happens so quick and if you,
you know, you're looking at the player
on film, you can watch as many games as
you want to watch, but you really don't
have an opportunity to know who that
person is. Unlike the draft where you
have so many uh touch points from our
scouts, from our coaches, from prodays,
from visits and combine. So you just
have to be very uh careful with the type
of people that you're bringing in in
free agency.
>> Speaking of that, you have been buy your
team on and off.
>> Just a professionalism, a comfort.
You know, I would say that the
consistency in which he operates and
functions has been very impressive over
the time that I've known Kevin.
>> He cut me off.
>> I didn't realize you were.
>> Go ahead. He said that he thinks that
you're a little bit more tame now
compared to when you first started at
>> We'll have to see when he gets here.
>> How how your relationship though evolved
over those?
>> I mean, he started I was, you know,
first time head coach and then I had to,
you know, be able to implement a program
that I felt like was
um best for for our team and what they
needed in Tennessee. Um,
>> you know, I guess I'm as tame as I need
to be.
>> Mike, speaking of fire
players that you've had in the past, how
do you guard against having like a blind
spot of those guys? Do you like
>> We always want to bring in talented
players. Um,
you know, whether we um knowing them is
important, but also talent is important,
too. Um, so again, we'll try to manage
what we feel like are the people that we
bring in and that we know and compared
to their talent level.
>> How seriously do you take players
concerns on that NFL report card,
especially with a team playing?
>> Don't want to focus on the report card.
I want to focus on what our players say
to to me and to stretch and anybody in
our organization. We we constantly are
are asking them. you know, we have a
leadership uh group that we believe in
and that we trust. Um, we won't be able
to make every recommendation. We won't
be able to do every single thing that
they want to do, but we listen to them
and we try to um add things to the
training room. We try to add equipment.
I I know for a fact on numerous
occasions uh players have asked about
different modalities in the training
room. I've gone to gym uh asked them to
order it on the stretch. You know,
Jonathan and Robert have gladly okayed
it.
Something came across my desk the other
day. Hey, we added this last year. We It
works out so good, we want to add
another one. Uh so, we're constantly
trying to get feedback uh from the
players on things that we can do to to
to help them do their job.
>> Gonzalez, um interesting. You guys have
an opportunity to pick up his fifth year
option. Um
we haven't picked it up. We should pick
it up.
perhaps extend him. He's going into the
year making
>> we want to make sure that we draft
extremely well and then we identify the
guys that uh we want to keep with us uh
and that have earned uh long-term uh
extensions with us and Christian Gonzo
is certainly one of those players and
you know but I can't comment on the
negotiations. Mike, the last time we
talked to you, I think you you mentioned
maybe challenging your staff to come
back with new ideas. I'm actually
curious from from your perspective, like
who do you turn to, whether it's read a
book, um, you know, mentors to to come
up with your own like new ideas for how
to keep things fresh?
I think that uh you know our staff and
and you know stretch you know obviously
um
you know different coaches around our
league or other leagues you know you
know Joe does such a great job with with
the Celtics you know just the start that
they've been able to have without
Jason has been really really impressive.
So, a lot of communications uh with him
and other coaches, you know, around the
league and, you know, a lot of thought.
I think you try to bounce ideas off of
really just come up with something,
think about it, you know,
give it some time. How do you enhance
it? How do you There's a lot of time in
the offseason. So, but try to be
intentional and just never want to be uh
gimmicky with what we do with players.
Mike, what's the best
>> thoughts of player development where it
comes to a guy who's got versatility,
trying not to give them too much as they
think of the
>> Well, uh, you talking about a young
player, Buck, or you talk Yeah, just
making sure that they don't get
overloaded and that they can get, um,
proficient at something.
Uh, and then I I'd say the better they
do, the the more uh we would try to give
them, you know, whether that
uh is a offensive lineman that may play
two positions or a receiver that may
play uh multiple positions, but you
know, certainly we try to figure out
what the player uh does best and do that
and then see what else they can do to
add and enhance that.
>> Isn't that pretty identify when they
start to swim a little bit?
>> I think so. I think when you start to
see him slow down, you know, when a
player, you know, one coach um which I
thought was was really um insightful was
like sometimes you can't tell the
difference between a player
that doesn't know what to do or one
that's afraid to do it. They're both
pretty slow and not very um reactive.
And so we have to try to measure what
that looks like on the field and then
maybe pull back on some stuff. team
released Josh Dos last week
[clears throat] to add a third
quarterback to the roster at some point.
>> Yeah, we needed we need a third arm and
you know try to find a a young guy that
you know we can develop and uh you know
potentially add to the to the roster
whether that's on the 53 man roster or
the practice squad.
>> Anyway,
>> does that in any way speak to Drake's
maturity and development that you can
take on a younger guy or
>> I think that's probably pretty accurate.
You know, I think that I really
appreciative of what um Josh did for us
coming in last year with Drake going
into his second year and uh I've
communicated that with Josh and said I
think it's just a different situation
now. So that's probably pretty accurate.
>> Get them Stacy.
You guys need tight end.
>> Well, I love them. Give nine of them.
>> Give them all.
>> Bring as many tight ends as we can get.
>> Is that going to be something you look
at in April? I hope. Yeah, I hope
there's a good uh again I think just
trying to find uh
you know the right guy. There's
different you know some of them are
receiving, some of them are more the
line of scrimmage, some of them a little
bit of both, you know. So I think we'll
just try to come up with the one that
fits us best and see where we can draft
them.
>> Earlier not to think back to back
somebody else but ask about this.
>> What do you got Nicole?
uh with the 31st pick. Do you feel that
that needs to
>> You sound like Roger Goodell [laughter]
with the 31st pick
>> in this year's draft?
>> Do you um should that be an immediate
impact player or are you comfortable
taking a player
>> best player available? Hopefully, maybe
we trade up. Maybe we trade out. I don't
know. But uh
you know, I I love being able to work
with with Elliot and Ryan. Elliot and
Ryan, their staff, coaching, and try to
bring that together. I'm trying to bring
the coach's perspective on a player and
and the personnel's side uh together to
to bring the best person in there for
our football team.
>> Thank you guys.
I appreciate